

MICHAEL DYE

FULLSTACK ENGINEER

CALL ME 615-423-2458

PROFILE

I use modern web technologies to build excellent user interfaces. While I specialize in the frontend, I also have strong knowledge of the backend, having built apps using Node.js, Express and MongoDB.

I enjoy learning new technologies and am continuously focused on adding new libraries, frameworks, languages, and design patterns to my toolbox. I also have plenty of experience building marketing sites for clients on popular CMSs, such as WordPress and Drupal.

CONTACT

Name Michael Dye

Mobile 615.423.2458

Email JoeyMDye@Gmail.com

Website JoeyDye.com

EDUCATION

School

Udacity

Degree Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree

School Degree Middle Tennessee State University Bachelors of Science in Journalism Minors in Marketing and Sociology

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- REACT / REDUX
- GATSBY / NEXT.JS
- REACT NATIVE
- JAVASCRIPT
- TYPESCRIPT
- NODE.JS / EXPRESS
- · CSS / SASS
- HTML
- · GIT
- WORDPRESS
- PHP
- REST / GRAPHQL

EXPERIENCE

FRONTEND DEVELOPER 07/2019 - 09/2020

CM Group

- Build modern JAMStack websites and applications in support of CM Group's sophisticated family of brands, using technologies such as React, Node.js, JavaScript, Gatsby, GraphQL, Firebase and Netlify.
- Assist leadership in building out team structure, processes and documentation.
- Cross-train fellow team members on the latest frontend technologies.
- Maintain legacy codebases on WordPress and Expression Engine.

• FREELANCE DEVELOPER 2018-PRESENT

Self-Employed

- Constructed exceptional WordPress websites for local businesses.
- Implemented custom functionality to support integrations with lead generation tools.

• FRONT-END DEVELOPER 2018-PRESENT

Horton Group

- Pioneered adoption of modern web frameworks, including React, React Native & Next.js.
- Developed Nissan Stadium WordPress website using PHP, SASS & JavaScript.
- Engineered modern JAM stack applications for clients on React and Firebase.
- Provided ongoing client support for React, WordPress and Drupal sites.
- Built peak-performing websites that exceeded quality and performance standards.
- Translated mocks to quality code using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Participated in technical planning and requirements gathering.
- Built custom assets that provided value and personalization to website users.

INTERACTIVE PROJECT MANAGER 2016-2018

Horton Group

- Managed 100+ interactive and marketing projects.
- Performed pre and post-launch QA and assisted with launch.
- Led discovery meetings and strategy calls.
- Provided WordPress trainings to clients.

ONLINE PRESENCE



LINKEDIN
https://www.linkedin.com/in/DyeJoey



CODEPEN
https://codepen.io/Joey-Dye





GITHUB https://github.com/JoeyDye